Summary

With experience across banking, logistics, and supply chain, I help companies achieve objectives by managing projects and coaching teams to consistently produce results. My project management work with PGW's route optimization team was recognized for excellence by TMW at their annual conference.

Skills

- · Appian Logistics Direct Route and DRTrack
- · Microsoft Windows and Office including Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Access, and Outlook
- PeopleNet
- SpeedGauge

Experience

Manager, Supply Chain Transportation Systems, TBC Corp. Palm Beach Gardens, FL, 2015 - 2018

- Managed deployment of PeopleNet Android Tablets, TMW Fleet Maintenance, Appian Direct Route and DRTrack Routing Software
- Wrote training manuals and Standard Operating Procedures for ~700 employees in seventy branches across three divisions
- · Planned complex inter-system IT software data flows in concert with IT staff
- · Created KPI reporting to support Business Process Improvements through positive driver behavior modification
- · Collaborated with HR group on safety procedures related to driver recruitment and retention
- · Presented strategic and tactical overviews to international executive committee
- · Designed templates in TMW Fleet Maintenance to reduce complexity for TBC's outsourced maintenance environment
- Negotiated service contracts with outside vendors for installs and ongoing maintenance of GPS systems

Product Implementation Manager, BNY Mellon, Inc. Pittsburgh, PA, 2013 - 2015

- Managed implementation of products and services for private banking, investments, and mortgage verticals
- Tested mobile and web electronic banking interfaces for B2B and B2C clients
- · Partnered with FIS Global on product development initiatives including mobile and web software
- $\bullet~$ Wrote business requirements and specifications for internal software development teams
- Analyzied and optimized processes for projects within the Wealth Management Division
- Facilitated Continuous Process Improvement for Private Banking Clients

Coordinator, Distribution Services, Pittsburgh Glass Works, LLC (formerly PPG Industries) Pittsburgh, PA, 2007 - 2013

- Directed implementation of Appian Direct Route and DRTrack logistics systems to 120 locations in 4 months
- · Wrote and disseminated branch Standard Operating Procedures related to fleet, route optimization, and mobile technology
- · Partnered with the Safety team to support initiatives for ongoing daily operations
- Drove expense reductions of \$2 million by using dynamic routing and fleet resource reductions enabled by route optimization software
- $\bullet \ \ Ensured \ optimal \ use \ of the \ Route \ Optimization \ software \ as \ analyst, \ administrator, \ and \ training \ specialist$
- · Championed branch usage by monitoring financials, making training recommendations, and optimizing changes to the route structures
- · Managed significant operational savings using GE and Donlen Fleet including budgets, maintenance, reductions, repairs, and orders
- Reduced average number of days between repair and return from an industry-trailing 1.57 to an industry-leading 0.50 in four years

Education

Bachelor of Arts, La Roche College Pittsburgh, PA, 2003

Graduated Cum Laude with 3.68 GPA.